From BBC learning English.
Com Hello and welcome to 6 Minute English on nail
and I'm rub in this program with talking about finance
and in particular planning for a future Lifestyles.
I can barely afford my current Lifestyle the same here,
but perhaps it will pick up some good tips today
a full that though a question being a millionaire that
may be an Impossible Dream for most of us.
When was the wood first used in English.
Was it a the 1600s David 1700cc?
The 1800's?
What do you think?
Rob?
I'm going to guess that it's the 1600s as that
of always being very wealthy people.
Well,
I'll reveal the sun set later.
Now to BBC Money Box,
program covers all sorts of financial features recently.
They were talking about lifestyle financial planning,
which is planning your finances to make the kind of
lifestyle.
You want to have Judy Lord,
leave the financial planning organization,
and she talked about the process of Lifestyle,
financial planning.
How many numbers does she say?
You need to start with?
Well,
we would start by saying that we need to put
together a lifetime Cash Flow,
full cast,
a role model.
You just need phone numbers,
your income expenditure assets liabilities,
and then we can project forward to show you what
sort of Lifestyle you will have.
If you do nothing at all.
And if indeed you do some of the things that
pops and ice or a pension,
or any other kind of financial product might help you
with.
So,
how many numbers do you need?
She says that you start with just four numbers.
That's right.
The first of these numbers is your income.
This is the money that you have coming in your
salary.
For example,
then there's the number for your expenditure.
This is the money you have going out for rent
food and statement to transport.
And so on.
The next number was for assets.
This is the cash value of things that you own
a free sample property.
Cause Julie is Bella savings and Investments,
that kind of thing.
And finally,
that is liabilities.
This is the money that you owe for example,
on credit cards or loans.
So,
if you Play these details.
She says they can come up with a lifetime cash
flow forecasts,
which is a calculation of how much money you can
expect to have in the future.
If that is enough to meet your expectations.
Do you have those details?
Do you know you'll numbers rub?
I have a very detailed spreadsheet where I do list
my income and expenditure.
So I do know from month-to-month how much money I
need and how much I can spend all that sounds
very organized.
What does it tell you about your future?
Where?
It just reminds me of exactly how much money I
don't have quite depressing.
How about you kneel or I?
Live in Blissful ignorance?
I have no idea how big my debts are.
I try not to worry about it.
I kind of think I'm not too young to worry
about it.
Now that as if by Magic,
it will all work out in the end.
So it would be difficult for me to come up
with those phone numbers.
Anyway,
let's listen to Julie.
Lord,
again,
describing the lifestyle financial planning process.
Well,
we would start by saying that we need to put
together a lifetime Cash Flow full,
cast Dora mobile.
You just need phone numbers,
your income expenditure assets liabilities,
and then we can project forward to show you what
sort of Lifestyle you will have if you do nothing
at all.
And if indeed you do some of the things that
pops a nice or a pension or any other kind
of financial product might help you with his lifestyle financial
planning,
all the people with a good pension North Dakota to
Judy Lord,
but
with stuff these Financial product,
no idea.
Really what they are all more importantly,
what we going to do for us.
So,
can you give us a hand to look to help
us?
Look forward to see what will happen?
So she also has younger clients.
Who wants for her company's help.
Yes.
She uses the phrase,
give us a hand,
which means to help someone.
If you give someone a hug and you help them
exactly in the way that I'll give you a hand
with 6 Minute English.
Well,
I think I give you a hand rather than the
other way around.
Really.
Well.
Let's not say fool out about it.
Let's listen to Judy North again.
Well,
it's not a little about old age.
They sent me.
There are people that we have quite a number of
younger clients who come to us and say,
we just want to get financially organized.
We've heard about all this stuff.
These Financial product,
no idea.
Really,
what they are all more importantly,
what we going to do for us.
So,
can you give us a hand to look to help
his looks forward to see what will happen?
It's nearly time now,
to review our vocabulary,
but first,
let's have the alarm set to all quiz question.
When was the word millionaire first used in English?
Was it a,
the 1600 and 1700 or see the 1800's?
What did you think?
Rob would like guests and said it was the 1600s.
Well,
not a good,
guess this time.
I'm afraid that felt like it was the 1800s.
When it was first used in a list though.
It had appeared in French in the 1700 now on
to the vocabulary.
Yes.
We had a lot of financial terms in this program.
We had cash-flow forecast.
This is a calculation of how much money you can
expect to have at a particular time in the future
and the cash flow forecast is based on knowing your
income,
which is the money you have coming in and your
expenditure,
the money you have going out.
You also need to know your assets,
which is the value of things you own,
as well as savings and Investments.
This is balanced again.
Your liabilities,
which is the term for the money that you owe,
for example,
on credit cards.
And finally,
we have the expression to give someone a hand meaning
to help someone.
Well,
that's all from us.
And this program.
We look forward to your company,
next time,
until then you can find us in all the usual
places on social media online and on a app to
search for BBC,
learning English by and thanks for getting me know.
Thank you for giving me a heads by English.
Thank you so much for watching this video.
I hope you enjoyed it.
We have many more exciting videos to help you improve
your English.
So be sure to subscribe to our channel,
to get the full experience of our YouTube channel.
See you there.