SIX LAT ANGUISH
FROM B B C LEARNING ENGLISH TOT CALM
HALLO AND WELCOME TO SIX MINUTE ENGLISH I'M NEAL AND I'M ROB
IN THIS PROGRAMME WE ARE TALKING ABOUT FINANCE AND IN PARTICULAR
PLANNING FOR A FUTURE LIFE STYLES
I CAN BARELY AFFORD MY CURRENT LIVE STYLE OUR SAME HERE
UT PERHAPS WE'LL PICK UP SOME GOOD TIPS TO DAY
EFORE THAT THOUGH A QUESTION
BEING A MILLIONAIRE MAY BE AN IMPOSSIBLE DREAM FOR MOST OF US BUT WHEN WAS THE WORD FIRST USED IN ENGLISH
WAS IT A
SIXTEEN HUNDREDS
BE THE SEVENTEEN HUNDREDS OR SE THE EIGHTEEN HUNDREDS WHAT DO YOU THINK ROB
I AM GOING TO GUESS THAT IT'S THE SIXTEEN HUNDREDS
S THERE HAVE ALWAYS BEEN VERY WEALTHY PEOPLE
WELL I'LL REVEAL THE ANSWER LATER NOW THE BABY SE MONEY BOX PROGRAMME COVERS ALL SORTS OF FINANCIAL FEATURES
RECENTLY THEY WERE TALKING ABOUT LIFE STYLE FINANCIAL PLANNING
WHICH IS PLANNING YOUR FINANCES TO MEET THE KIND OF LIFE STYLE YOU WANT TO HAVE
JULY LAUD LEADS A FINANCIAL PLANNING ORGANIZATION
AND SHE TALKED ABOUT THE PROCESS OF LIFE STYLE FINANCIAL PLANNING
HOW MANY NUMBERS DOES SHE SAY YOU NEED TO START WITH
WHILE WE WERE START BY SAYING THAT WE NEED TO PUT TOGETHER A LIFETIME CASHFLOWORECAST OR A MODEL
OU JUST NEED FOUR NUMBERS YOUR INCOME YOUR EXPENDITURE AR SETS LIABILITIES AND THEN WE CAN PROJECT FORWARD TO SHOW YOU WHAT SORT OF LIFE STYLE YOU WILL HAVE
IF YOU DO NOTHING AT ALL
AND IF INDEED YOU DO SOME OF THE THINGS THAT PERHAPS AN ICE O OR A PENSION OR ANY OTHER KIND OF FINANCIAL PRODUCT MIGHT HELP YOU WITH
SO HOW MANY NUMBERS DO YOU NEED
SHE SAYS THAT YOU START WITH JUST FOUR NUMBERS THAT'S RIGHT
THE FIRST OF THESE NUMBERS IS YOUR INCOME THIS IS THE MONEY THAT YOU HAVE COMING IN YOUR SALARY FOR EXAMPLE
THEN THERE'S THE NUMBER FOR YOUR EXPENDITURE
THIS IS THE MONEY YOU HAVE GOING OUT
FOR RENT FOOD ENTERTAINMENT TRANSPORT AND SO ON
THE NEXT NUMBER WAS FOR ASSETS
THIS IS THE CASH VALUE OF THINGS THAT YOU OWN FOR EXAMPLE PROPERTY CARSE JULRY AS WELL AS SAVINGS AND INVESTMENTS THAT KIND OF THING
AND FINALLY THERE IS LIABILITIES THIS IS THE MONEY THAT YOU OWE FOR EXAMPLE ON CREDIT CARDS OR LOANS
SO IF YOU KNOW THESE DETAILS SHE SAYS THEY CAN COME UP WITH A LIFETIME CASHFLOW ORECAST
WHICH IS A CALCULATION OF HOW MUCH MONEY YOU CAN EXPECT TO HAVE IN THE FUTURE
IF THAT IS ENOUGH TO MEET YOUR EXPECTATIONS
O YOU HAVE THOSE DETAILS
OU KNOW YOUR NUMBERS RO
I HAVE A VERY DETAILED SPREAD SHEET
WHERE I DUE LIST MY INCOME AND EXPENDITURE
SO I DO KNOW FROM MONTH TO MONTH HOW MUCH MONEY I NEED
ND HOW MUCH I CAN SPEND ARE THAIT SOUNDS VERY ORGANIZED
DOES IT TELL YOU ABOUT YOUR FUTURRE
WELL IT JUST REMINDS ME OF EXACTLY HOW MUCH MONEY I DON'T HAVE
S QUITE DEPRESSING HOW BOUT YOU KNEEL
OH I LIVE IN BLISSFUL IGNORANCE I HAVE NO IDEA HOW BIG MY DEBTS ARE
TRY NOT TO WORRY ABOUT
KIND OF THINK IAM MUCH TOO YOUNG TO WORRY ABOUT IT NOW
AS IF BY MAGIC IT WILL ALL WORK OUT IN THE END
SO IT WOULD BE DIFFICULT FOR ME TO COME UP WITH THOSE FOUR NUMBERS
AND H WAINT LETS LISTEN TO JULY LORD AGAIN
DESCRIBING THE LIFE STYLE FINANCIAL PLANNING PROCESS
WHILE WE WARE TARTEDBY SAYING THAT WE NEED TO PUT TOGETHER A LIFETIMECASHFLOW ORECAST OR A MODEL
OU JUST NEED FOUR NUMBERS YOUR INCOME YOUR EXPENDITURE ARE SETS LIABILITIES AND THENG WE CAN PROJECT FORWARD TO SHOW YOU WHAT SORT OF LIFE STYLE YOU WILL HAVE
IF YOU DO NOTHING AT ALL
AND IF INDEED YOU DO SOME OF THE THINGS THAT PERHAPS AN ICER OR A PENSION OR ANY OTHER KIND OF FINANCIAL PRODUCT MIGHT HELP YOU WITH
S LIFE STYLE FINANCIAL PLANNING ONLY FOR OLDER PEOPLE WITH A GOOD PENSION
NOT ACCORDING TO DULY LAW
WELL IT'S NOT ALL ABOUT OLD AGE RIS IT AMEN THERE ARE PEOPLE WE HAVE QUITE A NUMBER OF YOUNGER CLIENTS WHO COME TO US AND SAY WE JUST WANT TO GET FINANCIALLY ORGANIZED WE'VE HEARD ABOUT ALL THIS STUFF THESE FINANCIAL PRODUCT
NO IDEA REALLY WHAT THEY ARE OR MORE IMPORTANTLY WHAT THEY'RE GOING TO DO FOR US
SO CAN YOU GIVE US A HAND TO LOOK TO HELP US LOOK
FORWARD TO SEE WHAT WILL HAPPEN
SO SHE ALSO HAS YOUNGER CLIENTS
WHO ASKED FOR HER COMPANY'S HEL
YES SHE USES THE PHRASE GIVE US A HAND WHICH MEANS TO HELP SOME ONE
IF YOU GIVE SOME ONE A HAND YOU HELP THEM
EXACTLY IN THE WAY THAT I GIVE YOU A HAND WITH SIX MINUTE ENGLISH
WELL I THINK I GIVE YOU A HAND RATHER THAN THEOTHER WAY ROUND EEL
REALLY WELL LET'S NOT TER FALL OUT ABOUT
EUS LISTEN TO DULY LAUD AGAIN
WELL IT'S NOT ALL ABOUT OLD AGE S ITOMY THERE ARE PEOPLE H T WE HAVE QUITE A NUMBER OF YOUNGER CLIENTS WHO COME TO US AND SAY WE JUST WANT TO GET FINANCIALLY ORGANIZED WE'VE HEARD ABOUT ALL THIS STUFF THESE FINANCIAL PRODUCT
NO IDEA REALLY WHAT THEY ARE OR MORE IMPORTANTLY WHAT THEY'RE GOING TO DO FOR US
SO CAN YOU GIVE US A HAND TO LOOK TO HELP US LOOK
FORWARD TO SEE WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IT'S NEARLY TIME NOW TO REVIEW OUR VOCABULARY BUT FIRST LET'S HAVE THE ANSWER TO OUR QUIZ QUESTION
WHEM WAS THE WORD MILLIONAIRE FIRST USED IN ENGLISH WAS IT A THE SIXTEEN HUNDREDS B THE SEVENTEEN HUNDREDS OR C THE EIGHTEEN HUNDREDS
DID YE THINK RUP
WELL I GUESSED AND SAID IT WAS THE SIXTEEN HUNDREDS WELL NOT A GOOD GUESS THIS TIME I'M AFRAID
ZACTLY A LOT LATER IT WAS THE EIGHTEEN HUNDREDS WHEN IT WAS FIRST USED IN ENGLISH
THOUGH IT HAD APPEARED IN FRENCH IN THE SEVENTEEN HUNDRE
GOW ON TO THE VOCABULARY YES WE HAD A LOT OF FINANCIAL TERMS IN THIS PROGRAMME
WE HAD CASHFLOU FORECAST
THIS IS A CALCULATION OF HOW MUCH MONEY YOU CAN EXPECT TO HAVE
AT A PARTICULAR TIME IN THE FUTURE
AND THE CASH FLOE FORECAST IS BASED ON KNOWING YOUR INCOME WHICH IS THE MONEY YOU HAVE COMING IN
ND YOUR EXPENDITURE
THE MONEY YOU HAVE GOING OUT
YOU ALSO NEED TO KNOW YOUR ASSETS WHICH IS THE VALUE OF THINGS YOU OWN AS WELL AS SAVINGS AND INVESTMENTS
THIS IS BALANCED AGAINST YOUR LIABILITIES
WHICH IS THE TERM FOR THE MONEY THAT YOU OWE FOR EXAMPLE ON CRITIT CARDS AND FINALLY WE HAVE THE EXPRESSION TO GIVE SOME ONE A HAND MEANING TO HELP SOME ONE
WELL THAT'S ALL FROM US IN THIS PROGRAMME WE LOOK FORTO YOUR COMPANY NEXT TIME UNTIL THEN YOU CAN FIND US IN ALL THE USUAL PLACES ON SOCIAL MEDIA ON LINE AND ON OUR
JUST SEARCH FOR BE BESEEK LEARNING ENGLISH BY
THANKS ROB FOR GIVING ME A HAND NO THANK YOU FOR GIVING ME A HAND
I
SXMI EBISH FROM THE BBY SIN
HANK YOU SO MUCH FOR WATCHING THE SPEDIO I HOPE YOU ENJOYED IT
WE HAVE MANY MORE EXCITING VIDIARS TO HELP YOU IMPROVE YOUR ENGLISH
SO BE SURE TO SUBSTRIBE THOUGH OUR CHANNEL
TO GET THE FULL EXPERIENCE OF OUR UTUAE PHANNEL
SEE YOU THERE